Florinda Sgueglia

Product Designer | UX-UI



† Italy

**** +39 3331853774

▼ florinda.sgueglia@gmail.com

Linkedin ↗

Portfolio **↗**

About Me

UX/UI Designer with 10 years of experience in user interfaces, graphic and product design... *learn more* Bilingual:

Italian (native) | English (proficient)

Key competencies

User Iterface Design
User Experience Design
Design Thinking
Ux Research
Wireframing
Design System
Prototyping
Infographic
Motion graphic Design
Brand Identity

Tools

Figma - Figjam - Adobe Suite Sketch - Miro - InVision -Framer - HTML / CSS

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE & SKILLS

Deliveristo - Senior Product Designer

2023-Present

- Designing a brand new SaaS platform
- Building Design System consistent with the company's existing products (e-commerce website and app), while dealing with eventual iterations on the latter
- Cooperating with UX Researcher and Data-analyst for a more data-driven design approach
- Providing interactive prototypes either for usability tests and sales purpose
- Managing handoff to devs and supervising bug-fixing and QA after building

Freelance - Product Designer / UX-UI

2023-Present

- Designing and building user interfaces and Responsive websites
- Conducting UX Research (from competitor analysis to user interviews and gaining insights)
- Producing lo-fi and hi-fi wireframes
- Building Interactive prototypes

Engine Group Ltd UK. – Graphic Production & Developer 2019-2022

- Part of a specialist team to manage and build **apple.com** website for all European countries, from the layout and structure to the UI and local images
- Combining design and development acumen to provide compelling and engaging graphics, with strategic code
- Assisting the client to develop unique and customised interfaces by providing UI support
- Aligning client vision to project objectives and business goals in order to succeed and enable profitable results

Freelance - Graphic & Product Designer **2016-2019**

- Energydrop, IoT Technology Company. Establishing brand and corporate identity, developed company responsive website
- Dentist Clinic. Producing digital and motion graphic designs, developing company responsive website
- Radio Tahuania, independent music band. Producing motion graphic designs and animated video clip; designing CD covers

Laura Biagiotti Watches&Jewels. – Lead Designer 2012-2016

- · Innovating the annual watches and jewellery collections
- Expanding brand presence and market penetration by managing international fairs and supervising the ADV materials.

EDUCATION & TRAINING

✓ Ux Academy at DesignLab

2023

✓ BArch Industrial & Graphic Design at University of Campania "Luigi Vanvitelli"

2011